Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and here
today we have almost almost to
the end of our series on
giving a presentation in English.
This is part 9 of 10 so
this is near the end but
we've got a lot of really
great words and phrases
for discussing what you've
talked about in the last, I don't
know, 10 minutes or so. It's
the summary of your speech
and so that's what we're
going to talk about today.
That's right so let's
take a look at what Mr.
Ford is saying in his summary
and we'll be back in a bit.
Right everyone, I
apologize that I can't show
you the marketing
campaign today but next week
you will all have the
opportunity to see it for
yourselves and I have no
doubt that you will be impressed.
Let me wrap up
the presentation by
summarizing my key points.
As I mentioned at the outset,
2010 represents a key
year for alpha computers.
The recession is
hopefully behind us.
It is clear to everyone
in the computer industry
that demand is booming,
especially in the developing markets.
If we're to succeed in
this ultra-competitive
field then we really
need to push forward and
offer our customers
products that meet their
needs on all levels. As
I hope I've illustrated,
the X420 represents the
kind of computer that can
really satisfy those needs.
I gave you an idea of
the kind of revenue we
expect to hit in 2010 with
the new X420 range and
believe me this is really
just the beginning. Once
we establish the X420
in the market we have
plans to continue to expand
our range with ever
more revolutionary and
impressive products. Alpha
computers is dedicated to
innovation and
improvement. I really see no
limit in our potential
as long as we stick to the
principles I stressed earlier.
Quality, excellence and service.
Before we move on to the Q&A section, I'd
really like to leave you with a quote that
really sums up everything
that we've discussed today.
And hopefully it will provide you with
the same inspiration that it gives me.
As the great Henry Ford once
said, "quality means doing it
right when no one is
looking." Well, in fact,
our customers are looking.
They're looking for us
to lead the way in to
give them the quality that
our competitors cannot.
We cannot let them down.
All right, we're back.
So now let's take a look
at some language
on language takeaway.
Language takeaway. Some
are quite the very beginning of
today's monologue. We
have a phrase that basically
means the same
thing as summarize.
What was that phrase? That's
right. At the last sentence
of the first
paragraph, we see Mr.
Ford say, "let me wrap up the
presentation by summarizing my key points.
" So the phrase
there is "rap up.
" That means to
conclude, to finish, to end.
This is the very end of
his speech. And so to wrap
something up means
to finish it. That's right.
So maybe if you're giving a speech and
someone is telling you to wrap it up quickly.
I mean, stop. That's right.
He's fine at ending point.
So wrap it up. Let's go.
Come on. That's right.
So he's wrapping it up by
summarizing what he has talked about.
And so he goes back to the very
beginning and he says, "as
I mentioned at the outset."
Okay. The outset is a
noun. It's a time and it
means the beginning.
So you might remember in
parts one or two of this
speech that he was talking
about why 2010 is an
important year for their company.
And so this is the outset.
This is the beginning. You can
also say, you know, at the outset,
things looked bad. But it
turns out that they went well.
Okay. So outset means
beginning the start of something.
Mm-hmm. Okay. And he also talked about how
the computer industry demand is booming.
All right. So booming is an interesting
word because boom, the noun means boom.
So it's explode. Right.
It's a sound that you
hear when there's a storm. But
booming means doing very well.
That means that in this
case demand is booming.
There's a lot of
demand. That's right.
So when you hear people
say business is booming,
I mean, business
is going very well.
It's very successful. Okay.
So it basically means that it's
doing very well that
it's growing quickly and
rapidly. So he went on
to talk about the X420
and how the company
has plans to keep expanding
and keep coming out with
ever more revolutionary
and impressive products.
Okay. So something is
revolutionary if it
changes a situation. Okay.
Because revolution
basically means change.
But not a small change,
a really big change.
And so a product is
revolutionary if it introduces
something really new,
really exciting. Okay.
So an example of a revolutionary
product was the home computer.
Exactly. Because the home computer changed
the way people types and communicated
and did all these
different things.
And so it's revolutionary
because it introduced a big change.
That's right. Okay. So
revolutionary towards the end of Mr.
Ford's dialogue,
he said that they're
going to have a Q&A
section and he left us with
a quote that according
to him sums up everything
we've discussed today.
Okay. To sum up, this is
very related to the
word to summarize.
It means to say in fewer
words. Okay. So this quote says
what he wants to say, but it
says it in a very short space.
So if we read a book and I ask you
to sum up the story, this is basically
I'm asking for a
summary. That's right.
So I could say, you know,
the Harry Potter story is a story
about a young boy
who is a wizard who loses
his parents who goes
to school with his friends
and learns about his
powers. That's a perfect
way to sum up the Harry
Potter story. All right.
Very good. So that's about it
for language takeaway today.
But we have some
great phrases coming up
for you in fluency
builder. Let's listen to the
dialogue again first and
we'll be back in a moment.
Right everyone, I
apologize that I can't show
you the marketing campaign
today, but next week,
you will all have the opportunity
to see it for yourselves.
And I have no doubt
that you will be impressed.
Let me wrap up
the presentation by
summarizing my key points.
As I mentioned at the outset,
2010 represents a key
year for alpha computers.
The recession is
hopefully behind us.
It is clear to everyone
in the computer industry
that demand is booming,
especially in a developing markets.
If we're to
succeed in this ultra
competitive field, then we
really need to push forward
and offer our customers
products that meet their
needs on all levels. As
I hope I've illustrated,
the X420 represents
the kind of computer that
can really satisfy those
needs. I gave you an
idea of the kind of
revenue we expect to hit in
2010 with the new X420 range. And believe
me, this is really just the beginning.
Once we establish the X420
in the market, we have plans to
continue to expand
our range with ever more
revolutionary and impressive
products. Alpha computers
is dedicated to innovation
and improvement.
I really see no limit in
our potential as long as
we stick to the principles
I stressed earlier.
Quality, excellence and
service. Before we move on to
the Q&A section, I'd
really like to leave you
with a quote that really
sums up everything that
we've discussed today.
And hopefully it will provide
you with the same
inspiration that it gives me.
As the Great Henry
Ford once said, quality
means doing it right
when no one is looking.
Well, in fact, our customers are looking.
They're looking for us to lead the way
and to give them the quality that our
competitors cannot. We cannot let them down.
All right, we're back.
So now let's take a
look at four key phrases
on Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
So the first phrase
we've got here in Fluency
Builder is an interesting
one. And I think it's
important to point out
because we've got a verb
and a noun that
often go together. Mr.
Ford said this kind of computer can really
satisfy those needs that customers have.
That's right. So the phrase
there is to satisfy a need.
And as you said,
this verb and this
noun usually go together.
You want to satisfy your
customers' needs. All
right, so what do I need?
I need a good computer
that is fast that I can
do my business on. And
this computer, the X420,
satisfies that need.
It does what I need it to do.
Okay. So we understand
the verb to satisfy
and but the phrase is
a very powerful phrase,
especially if you use it
in business where you're
saying we are giving
our customers what they
need and we are making
them happy. Exactly.
Okay. As he continued talking about the
X420, he said if this is just the beginning.
All right. So this is something we often
say when we have a long project or plan,
you can say, you know, yes, things are
good now, but this is just the beginning.
All right, there are many
good things to come.
And this is something we
often say in a positive way.
You know, yes, this is good, but
expect better things in the future.
Very good. Okay. So
this is just the beginning.
And well, as he continued
talking about the company,
he said that the customers are
looking for us to lead the way.
Okay. So this is an
interesting phrase because
he's making a comparison
with other companies and
he's saying, listen, our
customers have many
needs, but they want us
to really be ahead of them
and to innovate and to
make new things and new
computers that will be
ahead of the competition.
So take the lead, be in the front.
So basically the phrase
to lead the way is for you
to be in the front and
give people a clear path.
Think of your saying bolts that runner in
the Olympics. Everyone's running quickly,
but all of a sudden
he takes the lead.
He leads the way. He is
ahead of everyone else.
All the other runners
are far, far behind him.
That's right. Okay. So
he's leading the way.
And he finishes his monologue
by saying we cannot let them down.
We cannot let our
customers down basically.
So the phrase here is
to let someone down.
He let me down.
We let them down.
This is a great phrase and
you can use it about anybody.
And it's a really important phrase
because it means to disappoint someone.
So for example, Marco, when you
forgot my birthday, you really let me down.
Okay. So that means I disappointed
you because I forgot your birthday.
So to let someone
down is to disappoint
them, to not do what
you were expected to do.
Exactly. And so a
company can do this.
For example, when a company
like Toyota makes a car that
has many problems, that
company lets down its customers.
So you can let someone down.
Basically, you have to have
the subject. You let someone
down or the company
let down its customers.
Exactly. Okay. A lot
of great stuff here.
Why don't we take one last
listen and boy back in a bit.
Right. Everyone, I apologize that I can't
show you the marketing campaign today.
But next week, you will all have the
opportunity to see it for yourselves.
And I have no doubt
that you will be impressed.
Let me wrap up the presentation
by summarizing my key points.
As I mentioned at the outset, 2010
represents a key year for alpha computers.
The recession is
hopefully behind us.
It is clear to everyone in
the computer industry that
demand is booming, especially
in the developing markets.
If we're to succeed in this ultra competitive
field, then we really need to push
forward and offer our
customers products that
meet their needs on
all levels. As I hope I've
illustrated, the X420
represents the kind of
computer that can
really satisfy those needs.
I gave you an idea of the
kind of revenue we expect
to hit in 2010 with
the new X420 range.
And believe me, this is
really just the beginning.
Once we establish the
X420 in the market, we
have plans to continue
to expand our range
with ever more revolutionary
and impressive products.
Alpha computers is
dedicated to innovation
and improvement. I
really see no limit in our
potential as long as
we stick to the principles
I stressed earlier. Quality,
excellence and service.
Before we move on to the Q&A section, I'd
really like to leave you with a quote that
really sums up everything
that we've discussed today.
And hopefully it will provide you with
the same inspiration that it gives me.
As the great Henry
Ford once said, "quality
means doing it right
when no one is looking.
" Well, in fact, our customers are looking.
They're looking for us to lead the way
and to give them the quality that our
competitors cannot. We cannot let them down.
All right, guys. So this is the penultimate
lesson about presentation skills.
As you saw, we are
summarizing and concluding
the presentation. And
there are actually a lot of
great things here to
learn from, especially the
vocab where you're saying,
"Okay, let some things
up to wrap it up to conclude
to summarize the key points.
" Yeah. But there are
also some important
things coming up next
week. That's the very, very
last part of this series.
Because usually after
a presentation, there is a section
four questions and answers.
That's called Q&A.
And that's the topic
of our next show. So you
guys stay tuned for that.
All right. So we'll see
you guys next time.
And of course, if you have
any questions or comments,
you will always find us at
englishpop.com. See you
guys there. Bye. Bye.